David Robles

Contact

INFORMATION Phone: 415-515-4764

E-mail: drobles@gmail.com Twitter: @davidrobles

Linkedin: http://www.linkedin.com/in/drobles

Professional Summary Software Engineer and former Ph.D. student. As a software developer I believe in object oriented design and agile methodologies, and consistently employ test-driven development. I also have some interest in games programming.

My research area during my Ph.D. can be broadly described as Artificial Intelligence with a particular focus on Reinforcement Learning, Simulation-Based Search, Evolutionary Algorithms and Games.

EDUCATION

PhD Computer Science

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

2009 - 2013

Thesis: "Simulation-Based Search and Learning in Games"

MSc Computer Science

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom

2007 - 2008

BSc Information Systems Engineering

Institute of Technology and Higher Education of Monterrey

Hermosillo, Mexico

2001 - 2006

Work

Software Engineer

Experience

DotLoop

San Francisco, CA January 2013 - Present

I have worked as a back end Java engineer, developing the new version of dotloop.com. I have been responsible for designing and implementing new features and RESTful APIs in Spring MVC, that not only support the website but also the iOS mobile app.

Teaching Assistant

University of Essex

Colchester, United Kingdom October 2009 - March 2012

Preparation, marking and teaching of classes and laboratories for the following undergraduate and postgraduate courses:

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2011.

CE320 - Large Scale Software Scale Systems and Extreme Programming, Autumn 2011.

CE218 - Computer Game Programming, Spring 2011.

CE152 - Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2011.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2010.

CE212 - Web Application Programming, Spring 2010.

CE112 - Procedural and Object-Oriented Programming, Spring 2010.

CE705 - Programming in Java, Autumn 2009.

IT Systems Administrator

Camisa Development Group Hermosillo, Mexico March 2006 - May 2007

Network Administrator, Windows Server 2003, Active Directory, VPN, CRM Software, Sage SalesLogix.

SKILLS SUMMARY

Artificial Intelligence: Reinforcement Learning, Simulation-Based Search, Evolution-

ary Algorithms, Neural Networks, Game Theory.

Programming languages: Java, Ruby, Python, PHP, C.

Web Development: Ruby on Rails, PHP, JSP/Servlets, Spring MVC, HTML5, JavaScript,

CSS/Sass, JQuery.

Testing: JUnit, RSpec, Test::Unit. Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL. Cloud: Amazon EC2/S3, Heroku.

Tools: Git, Ant, Maven.

Scientific computing: Numpy, Matplotlib. OS: Unix/Linux, Mac OS X, Windows.

AWARDS Scholarship for MSc and PhD Computer Science degrees from the National Council of

Science and Technology of Mexico.

CERTIFICATIONS Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA), February 2006.

Microsoft Certified Systems Administrator (MCSA), May 2007.